- Hi, I'm Ricky Harper,
- 嗨，我是Ricky Harper，
and I'm here floating in space
我现在正在太空中漂浮，
to show you how qualified I am
来向你们展示我有多么适合
for the Rocket Science Industries'
Rocket Science Industries的
Junior Astronaut Program.
初级宇航员计划。
- Space alien attack! - Stop it.
- 外星人攻击！ - 别闹了。
You're ruining my application.
你正在毁掉我的申请。
- Uh-oh, must find space fire hydrant.
- 哎呀，必须找到太空消防栓。
both: Asteroid attack!
两人：小行星攻击！
[thudding]
[砰砰声]
- So as you can see, not only can I survive
所以，如你所见，我不仅能在这场外星人和小行星的攻击中幸存，
an alien and asteroid attack,
还能在这群烦人的生物——我的四胞胎兄弟姐妹的攻击中存活。
I can also survive the attack of these annoying life-forms
所以，选我吧，Ricky Harper。
known as my fellow quadruplets.
如果有人需要空间……
So choose me, Ricky Harper.
那就是我。
If anyone needs space...
（外星声音）E.T. 捂住鼻子。
it's me.
说真的，我求你了。
- [alien voice] E.T. plug nose.
（外星声音）哎呀，太空鼻涕。
- Seriously, I'm begging you.
嘿，嘿，嘿，那是我的雪地靴吗？
- Ew, space snot.
是的。（外星声音）哎呀，你的脚真臭。
- Hey, hey, hey, are those my snow boots?
- Yes. - Eww, get your sweaty feet
out of them! - It's not sweaty feet.
It's a condition called "pedal hyperhidrosis."
It's just one of the ways I process stress.
But don't worry, right now, I'm perfectly calm.
[dripping]
Uh-oh.
[thud]
- Yeah, I don't see you getting into the program.
- Oh, I'm getting in, and I'm staying in because,
哦，我会进去的，而且我会留下来，因为，
unlike you three aimless drifters,
不像你们三个漫无目的的漂泊者，
I have a plan for my life.
我对自己的生活有一个计划。
- Yeah, well, I have a plan for my life.
是啊，我对自己的生活也有一个计划。
It starts with eating a pastrami sandwich for lunch.
它从午餐吃一个熏牛肉三明治开始。
- Well, Mae and I plan to eat pastrami all week,
嗯，梅和我计划整个星期都吃熏牛肉，
since she's staying with us while her parents are away.
因为她父母不在时她会和我们住在一起。
- My plan is to never have a plan.
我的计划是永远不要有计划。
Like, earlier, when I saw that pastrami in the fridge,
比如，早些时候，当我看到冰箱里的熏牛肉时，
I didn't plan on eating it all.
我并没有计划把它全吃掉。
I just did.
我就是这么做了。
- Well, while you drifters are focused on cured meats,
嗯，当你们这些漂泊者专注于腌制肉类时，
I'm going to make something of my life.
我要去成就一番事业。
Mae, let's go edit that video.
Mae，我们去编辑那个视频吧。
- I may have sent it right after you fell.
我可能在你们摔倒后立刻就发送了。
- What do you mean by "may," Mae?
你说的'可能'是什么意思，Mae？
- I mean, I did, did.
我是说，我确实发送了。
- That's okay. No sweat.
没关系。别担心。
Ahh!
啊！
I have a condition!
我有病！
[upbeat music]
- ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, na, ♪
- ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na, na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ 一，二 ♪ - ♪ 呐，呐，呐，呐，呐，呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
[upbeat music]
- Why isn't Rocket Science Industries getting back to me?
- 为什么火箭科学工业公司不回复我？
Maybe it's because they didn't get my video.
也许是因为他们没有收到我的视频。
- Or maybe it's because they did.
- 或者可能是因为他们确实收到了。
- You're right. Millions of kids probably
- 你说得对。可能有数百万的孩子
sent in videos. Why am I special?
发送了视频。我有什么特别的？
- You're not. - Totally average.
- 你并不特别。 - 完全普通。
- You're not even the best quad.
- 你甚至不是最好的四轴飞行器。
- No, this is where you're supportive
- 不，这时候你应该支持我
and say the opposite of those things.
并说些相反的话。
- Well, I guess that just wasn't part of our life plan.
- 好吧，我想那只是不属于我们的生活计划。
- Yeah, we're just a bunch of aimless drifters.
- 是的，我们只是一群漫无目的的漂泊者。
- Hey, pocket pastrami!
- 嘿，口袋里的熏牛肉！
Nope, just pocket.
不，只是口袋。
- Ugh, he's never gonna email me.
唉，他永远不会给我发邮件。
[beep]
哔
He just emailed me!
他刚刚给我发邮件了！
Lonny Tusk, the CEO of Rocket Science Industries,
Lonny Tusk，火箭科学工业公司的CEO，
says he just landed in Denver, and he's coming here!
说他刚到丹佛，正往这儿来！
- Actually, I'm already here.
实际上，我已经在这儿了。
- Ah!
啊！
Whoa, I-- I just got your email.
哇，我——我刚收到你的邮件。
How'd you get here so fast?
你怎么这么快就到了？
Jetpack? Hyper-loop?
喷气背包？超级环？
Molecular restructuring transporter?
分子重组传送器？
- Maybe he forgot to hit Send earlier.
也许他之前忘了点击发送。
- Dicky, he's Lonny Tusk,
迪基，他是朗尼·塔斯克，
the world's most brilliant rocket scientist.
世界上最杰出的火箭科学家。
He didn't forget to hit Send.
他没有忘记点击发送。
- Dude, I totally forgot to hit Send.
伙计，我完全忘了点击发送。
- Don't worry, I do it all the time.
别担心，我经常这样。
- Mm-hmm, anyway, Ricky, I came to offer you
嗯，不管怎样，里基，我来是想邀请你
a space in my Junior Astronaut Training Program.
参加我的少年宇航员训练计划。
- Yes! - Along with your brothers
- 是的！ - 还有你的兄弟们
and sister. - No!
和妹妹。 - 不！
- When I saw your video, it gave me an idea.
- 当我看到你的视频时，我有了一个想法。
We've put people in space, monkeys in space.
我们把人送上了太空，猴子送上了太空。
We've even put sea monkeys in space.
我们甚至把海猴送上了太空。
But never quadruplets.
但从未有过四胞胎。
- Quads in space?
- 四胞胎上太空？
Oh, no, you don't even want to put us in a minivan together.
哦，不，你甚至不想让我们一起坐进一辆小型货车。
- He's right. They made my dad quit car pool.
- 他说得对。他们让我爸爸放弃了拼车。
- No, this is perfect.
- 不，这太完美了。
My new space module requires four people to operate.
我的新太空舱需要四个人来操作。
And what better four people than you?
还有谁比你们四个人更适合呢？
- Any four people.
- 任何四个人。
- But you four are used to operating in tight quarters.
- 但你们四个习惯了在狭小的空间里工作。
You shared a womb.
你们曾经共享一个子宫。
- Uh, for a while, but Dawn moved out, like,
- 呃，虽然有一段时间，但Dawn两年前就搬出去了，有了自己的子宫。
two years ago and got her own womb.
- 而且还有那件事。
- And then there's that.
听着，Lonny，我已经准备好了。
Look, Lonny, I've prepared.
我有一个计划。他们没有。
I have a plan. They don't.
他们甚至不想去太空。
They don't even want to go to space.
- You guys wanna go to space?
- 你们想不想去太空？
- Yeah. - Sounds fun.
- 是的。 - 听起来很有趣。
- Why not? - Ooh, "why not?"
- 为什么不呢？ - 哦，'为什么不呢？'
Now, that's a great question.
现在，这是一个很棒的问题。
You could learn a lot from him.
你可以从他那里学到很多。
I got where I am today by asking "why not?"
我今天所处的位置是通过问'为什么不呢？'来实现的。
- Okay, why not... just take me?
- 好吧，为什么不...就带我去呢？
- Well, because it's my spaceship,
- 嗯，因为这是我的太空船，
and I want to take quadruplets.
我想带四胞胎。
So either get with the program
要么跟上节奏
or you're not getting in the program.
要么你就别想参与进来。
- I think you know what you need to say.
- 我想你知道该说什么。
- Why not? - Yes, that's the spirit!
- 为什么不？ - 对，就是这样！
Oh, this is gonna be so cool.
哦，这一定会很酷。
I'm gonna shoot you guys into space.
我要把你们射到太空去。
- Well if we're going to space, we better practice our moonwalk.
- 如果我们真的要去太空，我们最好练习一下月球漫步。
- Are you sure the question isn't "why?"
- 你确定问题不是“为什么”？
- Yep, it's definitely "why not?"
- 是的，绝对是“为什么不？”
[laughs]
[笑]
Ooh, ooh! - Ooh!
哦，哦！
- Nice!
好极了！
♪ ♪
- Whoa!
哇！
This place looks exactly like I thought it would.
这个地方看起来和我预想的一模一样。
They even have models of all the planets.
他们甚至有所有行星的模型。
- Dude, those are just exercise balls.
老兄，那些只是健身球。
- This is a high-tech training facility
这是一个高科技训练设施
designed by the world's leading innovator in space exploration.
由世界领先的空间探索创新者设计。
They're not exercise balls.
它们不是健身球。
- Dude, they're totally just exercise balls.
- 哥们，它们完全就是健身球。
- Here, catch Uranus.
- 来，接住天王星。
- Oof!
- 哎哟！
- Tom, why are we letting the kids go to space?
- 汤姆，我们为什么要让孩子去太空？
- Why not?
- 为什么不呢？
- I see where Dicky gets it. - Oh, hey.
- 我明白迪基是怎么想的了。 - 哦，嘿。
- We don't even let the kids ride the bus by themselves.
- 我们甚至不让孩子们自己坐公交车。
- Don't worry, no one goes into space
- 别担心，没有人未经适当训练就进入太空的。
without being properly trained, which is why your kids
- 这就是为什么你的孩子将每隔一个周末都在这个设施里度过。
will spend every other weekend in this facility
- 直到他们十八岁。
until they're eighteen.
直到他们十八岁。
- You're gonna take our kids away for two weekends a month?
- 你要每个月带走我们的孩子两个周末？
What is that gonna cost us? - It's free.
那要花费我们多少钱？ - 免费的。
- Can you make it three weekends a month?
- 你能每个月安排三个周末吗？
- We're right here.
- 我们就在这里。
- No, no, we just wanna make sure you guys
- 不，不，我们只是想确保你们
are properly trained. - Yeah, think about how hard
得到适当的训练。 - 是的，想想这对我们来说有多难。
it's gonna be for us. - Oh, yeah, yeah.
- 哦，是的，是的。
- Yeah, all alone in that big house...
- 是的，在那大房子里独自一人...
- [sighs] - No kids.
- [叹气] - 没有孩子。
- No noise. - No chaos.
- 没有噪音。 - 没有混乱。
- Mm. - Don't worry.
- 嗯。 - 别担心。
Remember, I'm going to be with you this weekend.
记住，这个周末我会和你在一起。
- Oh, yeah, right.
- 哦，对，没错。
- Yay!
- 耶！
- All right, kids, your parents have to go.
- 好了，孩子们，你们的父母得走了。
Say your good-byes.
说再见吧。
[door creaks]
[门吱吱作响]
- I'm gonna miss you, Dawn. - Yeah, me too,
- 我会想你的，Dawn。 - 是啊，我也是，
but you better go. They're not gonna wait for you.
但你最好快走。他们不会等你的。
- Don't worry, you'll see them soon enough if you don't
- 别担心，如果你不
qualify for the program.
符合这个项目的要求，你很快就能见到他们。
- Wh--qualify?
- 什——符合？
I thought you wanted to send quadruplets into space.
我以为你想把四胞胎送进太空。
- I do--that's why you're competing
- 我是想——所以你们要
against other quadruplets.
和其他四胞胎竞争。
all: Hello, Harpers.
所有人: 你们好，哈珀家。
all: Hello, Kramdens.
所有人: 你们好，克拉姆登家。
- Hold on, Lonny was just about to tell us
- 等等，朗尼正要告诉我们
who our competition is.
我们的竞争对手是谁。
Who is it?
是谁？
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- Oh, my God, I'm sorry, Mae.
哦，天哪，对不起，梅。
I hate to interrupt you while you're doing your homework,
我不想在你做作业时打断你，
but if you wouldn't mind setting the--
但如果你不介意摆一下——
Table.
餐桌。
- I did it already, and my homework's done.
我已经摆好了，而且我的作业也做完了。
- Anne, someone stole our trash cans
安妮，有人偷了我们的垃圾桶
right out of the driveway!
直接从车道上！
- No, Mr. Harper, I put them on the street.
不，哈珀先生，我把它们放在街上了。
Tomorrow's trash pickup.
明天是垃圾收集日。
- But I didn't have to yell up the stairs four times
但我没有必要对着楼梯喊四次
for you to do it.
让你去做。
- And I didn't have to take away video games
我也没有必要拿走视频游戏
so she'd set the table.
让她摆桌子。
- Oh, I don't need to be told.
哦，我不需要被告知。
I see something that needs doing,
我看到需要做的事情，
I just do it.
我就去做。
- She just does stuff!
她就是做事！
[clunk]
[咚]
- What is she doing now?
- 她现在在做什么？
- It sounds like laundry.
- 听起来像是在洗衣服。
- Where should I put all this clean, folded laundry?
- 我应该把这些洗干净叠好的衣服放在哪里？
♪ ♪
- We are rocking these jumpsuits.
- 我们穿着这些连体衣很酷。
- I think mine's broken.
- 我觉得我的那个坏了。
This is how high I normally jump.
这是我通常跳的高度。
- Dicky, focus. The suits don't matter.
- 迪基，专注点。衣服不重要。
All that matters now is we beat the Kramdens.
现在最重要的是我们要打败克拉蒙一家。
They always get the best of us.
他们总是占我们的上风。
But them beating us is not in my plan.
但让他们打败我们不在我的计划之内。
all: Hello, Harpers.
大家：你好，哈珀一家。
all: Ahh!
大家：啊！
- Hey, they have really cool nicknames on their suits now.
- 嘿，他们现在在衣服上有很酷的昵称。
- It doesn't matter.
- 这无关紧要。
- Hello, Maverick. - Rocky.
- 你好，马弗里克。 - 洛基。
- Jazz. - Ice.
- 爵士。 - 冰。
- Really cool nicknames.
- 真的很酷的昵称。
- It still doesn't matter.
- 这仍然无关紧要。
- Well, how come they get nicknames?
- 好吧，为什么他们有昵称？
- Oh, right.
哦，对了。
All astronauts have cool nicknames.
所有宇航员都有酷炫的昵称。
Let's see, you're One, Two, Three, Four.
让我看看，你是1号，2号，3号，4号。
- Nice.
不错。
- Hey, that--that doesn't make any sense.
嘿，这——这说不通啊。
Why am I Number Two?
为什么我是2号？
all: [giggle]
（咯咯笑）
- You're Number Two.
你是2号。
- Well, we're gonna be number one once we
好吧，我们一旦踢了你们的小屁股，就会成为第一名。
kick your little butts.
我们会成为第一名。
- We were more scared when we thought we were
- 当我们以为我们要对抗海猴时，我们更害怕。
going up against sea monkeys. - Yeah.
- 是的。
- You took our commercial, you took our quad goals hashtag,
- 你们拿走了我们的广告，你们拿走了我们的四目标话题标签，
but you will not take space from us.
- 但你们不能从我们这里夺走空间。
- Yeah, you heard Number Two.
- 是的，你们听到了二号的话。
all: [giggling] Number Two.
- 全体：[咯咯笑] 二号。
- That means poop.
- 那意味着便便。
- It does.
- 确实。
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Okay, your first challenge is an easy one.
好的，你的第一个挑战很简单。
You're cruising toward Mars, and you hit an asteroid.
你正朝着火星前进，然后撞上了一颗小行星。
- Nice driving, Ricky.
开得不错，Ricky。
- It causes a fire in the hydrogen fuel system,
这导致了氢燃料系统起火，
and the only way to put it out is with water from your galley.
唯一的灭火方法是使用你厨房里的水。
- That should be easy.
那应该不难。
- Not if you're dizzy and spinning out of control.
如果你头晕目眩并失去控制的话就不容易了。
- Yeah, thanks again, Ricky.
是啊，再次感谢你，Ricky。
- So spin yourselves on these posts.
所以在这些柱子上旋转。
And put out your burning fuel systems.
并扑灭你们燃烧的燃料系统。
- What burning fuel systems?
- 什么燃烧的燃料系统？
- Those burning fuel systems.
- 那些燃烧的燃料系统。
And go!
出发！
- I got it! I--I--
- 我明白了！我——我——
I don't got it.
我不明白。
- Here, let me.
- 来，让我来。
I got it, I got it--oh! - Oh!
我明白了，我明白了——哦！ - 哦！
- I don't have it. - Wait, I have an idea.
- 我没有。 - 等等，我有个主意。
- Don't have time! - But I--
- 没时间了！ - 但我——
- Just--just go!
- 快——快走！
- This is dumb.
这太愚蠢了。
- Drinking the water? That's your big idea?
喝那水？这就是你的大计划？
- Brilliant! - Genius!
太棒了！
- How dizzy are you guys?
天才！
- Nice job, Harpers. all: Yes!
你们晕得厉害吗？
- Too bad the Kramdens put out their fire five seconds ago.
干得好，哈珀一家。
- Yes, yes! - Whoo!
可惜克雷姆登家五秒前就把火扑灭了。
all: Kramdens.
是的，是的！
- If you would've listened to Dicky the first time,
克雷姆登家。
you might've won.
如果你一开始就听迪基的，或许能赢。
all: Ricky.
大家：Ricky。
- Me!
我！
- That's some outside-the-box thinking, Four.
这真是跳出框架的思考，Four。
Just like my bees.
就像我的蜜蜂一样。
- Bees think outside the box?
蜜蜂会跳出框架思考吗？
- That's right, Number Two.
没错，Number Two。
That's why I keep them here, to inspire me.
这就是我留它们在这里的原因，为了启发我。
See, bees' roly-poly bodies are not designed to fly.
你看，蜜蜂那圆滚滚的身体并不适合飞行。
But they don't let "why" stop them.
但它们不会让‘为什么’阻止它们。
Somewhere along the way, an out-of-the-box thinking bee
在某个时刻，一只跳出框架思考的蜜蜂
decided to turn its wings on its axis,
决定在其轴上转动翅膀，
creating a helicopter effect, and up it went.
产生了直升机效应，然后它就飞起来了。
- Huh, fascinating.
- 嗯，真有趣。
Hey, could I change my nickname?
嘿，我能改个昵称吗？
Like, what about Bee-Man?
比如，Bee-Man怎么样？
- Bee-Man? I like it.
- Bee-Man？我喜欢。
Eh, it's too long though. I'm gonna call you BM for short.
不过，这名字太长了。我就简称你为BM吧。
all: BM.
所有人：BM。
- BM is another word for number two.
- BM还有“二号”的意思。
- I know what it means.
- 我知道那是什么意思。
- Okay, for your next challenge, there's been an oxygen breach
- 好的，你的下一个挑战是，主舱发生了氧气泄漏。
in the main cabin.
- 在主舱。
You have a rope, a plunger, a twelve-pack of toilet paper,
- 你有一根绳子，一个马桶塞，一打十二卷的卫生纸，
a box of tacos, and a whistle.
- 一盒塔可，和一个哨子。
You have to get to the escape pod
- 你必须在不踩到横梁的情况下到达逃生舱。
without your feet touching the beam.
- 第一个到达逃生舱并按下按钮的队伍获胜。
First team to hit the button at the escape pod wins.
- 开始！
Go!
- 好的。
- Okay. - Okay.
- We need to strategize.
- 我们需要制定策略。
- I've been strategizing my entire life for this moment.
- 我一生都在为这一刻制定策略。
Everything in that pile has a purpose, and I know
那堆东西里的每一样都有其用途，而且我
exactly what it is.
非常清楚它们是什么。
Now grab a roll of toilet paper.
现在拿一卷卫生纸。
- Why? - Because I don't know
- 为什么？ - 因为我不了解你，
about you, but I like speed.
但我喜欢速度。
Plunge! - Scooch!
跳！ - 滑！
- Whistle! [whistle tweets]
- 吹口哨！ [口哨声]
- Plunge! - Scooch!
- 跳！ - 滑！
- Whistle! [whistle tweets]
- 吹口哨！ [口哨声]
- Is this what you call speed?
- 这就是你所谓的速度吗？
- Imagine how slow we'd be if we didn't have these
- 想象一下，如果我们没有这些
ingenious toilet paper diapers.
巧妙的厕纸尿布，我们会慢成什么样。
Now plunge! - Scooch!
现在，跳！ - 滑！
- Whistle! [whistle tweets]
- 吹哨！ [哨声响起]
I really don't see the point of the whistle.
我真的不明白吹哨的意义。
- I really don't see the point of you saying "whistle."
- 我也不明白你说“吹哨”的意义。
I could just whistle after "scooch."
我可以在“滑”之后直接吹哨。
- Well, it doesn't matter.
- 嗯，这无关紧要。
The only thing that matters is that we're doing better
唯一重要的是我们在进步
than the Kramdens.
比克拉姆登夫妇强。
- Look at them, they're frozen, completely intimidated!
看他们，完全被吓呆了！
- Plunge! - Scooch!
跳！ 滑！
- Just to be clear, Lonny said we had to get to the escape pod
明确一下，朗尼说我们必须在不触碰横梁的情况下到达逃生舱。
without our feet touching the beam.
但他从未说过我们必须使用它，对吧？
- But he never said we had to use it at all, did he?
没错。
both: Nope.
而且他也没说我们必须使用这些物品，对吧？
- And he didn't say we had to use any of these items, right?
没错。
both: Nope.
那他们到底在干什么？
- Then what the heck are they doing?
跳！ 滑！
- Plunge! - Scooch!
- 跳水！ - 挪动！
- Whistle! - I have no idea.
- 吹口哨！ - 我完全不知道。
- Wait, we forgot the tacos.
- 等等，我们忘了带玉米卷。
- We have to go back.
- 我们必须回去。
[whistle tweets]
[口哨声]
- Reverse whistle. - Reverse scooch.
- 反向口哨。 - 反向挪动。
- Reverse plunge! - Wait!
- 反向跳水！ - 等等！
I ate the tacos.
我吃了玉米卷。
- Plunge!
- 跳水！
- What are you guys doing?
- 你们在干什么？
- Uh, winning.
- 呃，赢了。
- Don't you mean, "uh, losing?"
- 你不是想说，“呃，输了？”
[buzz]
[嗡嗡声]
- But they-- You can't do that.
- 但他们——你不能那样做。
Lonny said we have to use all of this stuff.
Lonny说我们必须用所有这些东西。
- Wait, did he? - I don't think he did.
- 等等，他说过吗？
- First you crash us into an asteroid and now this.
- 我不认为他说过。
Nice job, Poop.
- 先是让我们撞上小行星，现在又是这样。
- It's BM.
干得好，Poop。
♪ ♪
- 是BM。
- Hey, Mae, whatcha doing?
嘿，梅，你在做什么？
- Well, I finished the closets, so I was just
嗯，我整理完衣柜了，所以现在正
cleaning up Dawn's room a little.
稍微打扫一下道恩的房间。
- If there's any room that needs a cleaning, it's the boys' room.
如果有哪个房间需要打扫，那就是男孩们的房间。
- Oh, I did that too.
哦，我也打扫过了。
- Are you sure we can't pay you an allowance?
你确定我们不能给你点零花钱吗？
- Oh, no, my parents say it's important to learn
哦，不用，我父母说学习
good habits early so you can grow up to be
从小养成好习惯很重要，这样你长大后
a responsible adult and be prepared for the world.
才能成为一个负责任的成年人，并准备好面对世界。
- Your--your parents taught you all that?
你——你父母教你这些的？
- Yeah, just like you taught the quads.
是的，就像你教四胞胎那样。
- [laughs]
（笑）
- Did you teach them that? Because I know that I did not.
你教过他们那个吗？因为我知道我没有。
- Well, our kids aren't prepared for the world at all,
嗯，我们的孩子根本没准备好面对这个世界，
and now we're about to send them out of this world.
现在我们即将把他们送出这个世界。
Not only have we failed them.
我们不仅让他们失望了。
We have failed the entire space program.
我们还让整个太空计划失望了。
Come on.
来吧。
- To save the kids?
为了救孩子们？
- No, to save space!
不，为了拯救太空！
♪ ♪
- Ricky, what are you doing?
- 瑞奇，你在做什么？
We can still beat the Kramdens.
我们还能打败克拉姆登一家。
We can still go to space.
我们还能去太空。
This isn't over yet.
这还没结束呢。
- It is for me.
- 对我来说已经结束了。
All of my planning, all of my dreaming,
我所有的计划，所有的梦想，
for what?
为了什么？
I'm a complete loser.
我是个彻底的失败者。
- You're not a complete loser.
- 你不是个彻底的失败者。
- I'm standing in a puddle of my own foot sweat
- 我站在自己的脚汗形成的水坑里，
and wearing a toilet paper diaper.
还穿着用卫生纸做的尿布。
- He said you're not a complete loser.
- 他说你不是彻底的失败者。
- If I'm not gonna go to space, what am I gonna do with my life?
- 如果我不能去太空，我这辈子要干什么？
- You can't give up.
- 你不能放弃。
You just need to learn to be less Ricky
你只需要学会不那么像Ricky，
and think outside the box.
并且跳出思维定势。
- I thought I was thinking outside the box.
- 我以为我已经在跳出思维定势了。
Do I need to be further outside the box?
我需要更跳出思维定势吗？
Those bees are inside a box.
那些蜜蜂在一个盒子里。
Should I let them outside of their box?
我应该让他们离开他们的箱子吗？
Is that thinking far enough outside the box?
那是不是想得太超乎常规了？
- No, that would just be stupid.
- 不，那只是愚蠢。
- Everything I've ever learned in my life tells me those bees
- 我一生中学到的所有知识都告诉我那些蜜蜂
should stay inside that box, which can only mean one thing.
应该留在那个箱子里，这只能意味着一件事。
I have to set them free. - What are you doing?
我必须放它们自由。 - 你在做什么？
- Get outside the box!
- 跳出框架思考！
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
Get back inside the box!
回到箱子里去！
[buzzing]
[嗡嗡声]
We'll be safe in here.
我们会在这里安全的。
[buzzing] - Ah, it's followed us in here!
嗡嗡声 - 啊，它跟着我们进来了！
- Ah, uh, quick, here!
啊，呃，快，这里！
[buzzing] - Ah, it's in here too!
嗡嗡声 - 啊，它也在这里面！
[buzzing] - I'll get it.
嗡嗡声 - 我来处理。
Oh.
哦。
[alarm blares]
警报声大作
Hey, it's like a disco.
嘿，这就像个迪斯科。
[mimics disco music]
模仿迪斯科音乐
- Ready for launch in ten, nine, eight, seven...
准备发射，十，九，八，七...
- Wait, launch? Launch what?
- 等等，发射？发射什么？
- We're going into space!
- 我们要去太空了！
- Relax, we're probably in just some kind of simulator.
- 放松，我们可能只是在某种模拟器里。
- One, blast off.
- 一，发射。
[engines roaring]
[引擎轰鸣]
- Those simulated flames look pretty real.
- 那些模拟的火焰看起来相当真实。
- Trust me, if this were real, we'd have left the atmosphere
- 相信我，如果是真的，我们早就离开大气层
and be floating in zero gravity.
- 并且处于失重状态了。
- Whoa.
- 哇。
- Whoa! - Kind of like this.
- 哇！ - 有点像这样。
- We're in space! - We're in space!
我们在太空！我们在太空！
- Anybody else wish they were still wearing
还有人希望他们还穿着
the toilet paper diapers?
卫生纸尿布吗？
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- This is bad.
这很糟糕。
- I don't know, this floating thing's pretty cool.
我不知道，这种漂浮的感觉挺酷的。
- Yeah, it would be cool if we weren't in space!
是啊，如果不是在太空的话，确实很酷！
What are we gonna do?
我们该怎么办？
- We're not gonna worry.
我们不会担心的。
Here, Ricky knows stuff.
里基知道一些事情。
Ricky, we need your help.
Ricky，我们需要你的帮助。
- Why? I don't know stuff.
- 为什么？我不懂什么。
I know nothing.
我一无所知。
I'm an aimless drifter.
我是个漫无目的的漂泊者。
- Come in, Harpers, this is Mission Control.
- 请回答，Harpers，这里是任务控制中心。
Do you read?
- 能听到吗？
- Great, even in space they make you read.
- 太好了，即使在太空他们也让你读书。
- We're here. We read you.
- 我们在这里。我们听到了。
- How do we get home?
- 我们怎么回家？
- Everybody calm down.
- 大家都冷静下来。
There's nothing to worry about.
没什么好担心的。
[buzzing] - Uh-oh, there's another
【嗡嗡声】- 哎呀，这里还有一只蜜蜂。
bee in here. - I got it this time.
- 这次我来搞定它。
- Okay, the first thing you need to know is that--
- 好的，首先你需要知道的是——
[clang]
【铛声】
all: Ricky!
所有人：Ricky！
- Me!
- 我！
- Oh, great, main communications are out.
- 哦，太好了，主通讯系统坏了。
- Epstein, get the back-up com link online.
- Epstein，把备用通讯链接上线。
- Sorry to interrupt you, Mr. Tusk.
- 很抱歉打断您，Tusk先生。
We were just wanting to check in on our kids.
我们只是想看看我们的孩子们。
- We have video, still working on audio.
我们有视频，音频还在修复中。
- Well, you can see for yourself.
好吧，你自己看吧。
- Our kids are in space?
我们的孩子在太空？
- They're not in space.
他们不在太空。
They're in a space simulator.
他们在太空模拟器里。
- Well, that's a relief.
那倒是让人松了一口气。
- A very expensive space simulator
一个非常昂贵的太空模拟器
they're breaking more and more by the second.
他们每秒钟都在破坏更多东西。
- I'm sorry, Mr. Tusk, this is all out fault.
对不起，塔斯克先生，这都是我们的错。
- Maybe you should get them out of there
也许您应该让他们离开那里
before they break anything else. - Yeah.
在他们再弄坏其他东西之前。 - 是的。
- Too late.
太晚了。
- Oh, not the cup holders!
哦，不要是杯架！
- Can't we just open the door?
我们不能直接开门吗？
- No, once the simulator is activated, it can only
不行，一旦模拟器启动，只能
be deactivated from the inside with a specific code.
从内部用特定代码停用。
- Well, so give them the code!
那好吧，给他们代码！
- As soon as Epstein gets the back-up com link
一旦Epstein启动备用通讯链接
online, I will. - Well, hurry up, Epstein!
我就会给。 - 那快点，Epstein！
Oh, I am sorry, Epstein, you do your thing.
哦，对不起，Epstein，你忙你的。
- Relax, everything will be fixed in a matter of seconds.
放松，一切几秒钟内就能修复。
- Okay.
好的。
- Audio's back online.
音频恢复在线了。
They can hear us. [buzzing]
他们能听到我们。
- Ah, bee! - Huh?
啊，蜜蜂！
- Oh, ah, ah, nobody move, nobody move.
嗯？
- Ah!
哦，啊，啊，大家别动，别动。
[power down]
啊！
- Any chance you have a back-up to the back-up, Epstein?
你有没有备用的备用方案，Epstein？
- Ah, um, I am allergic to bees.
- 啊，呃，我对蜜蜂过敏。
- Oh, ooh!
- 哦，哦！
- Any chance you have a back-up Epstein?
- 你有没有备用的，Epstein？
- Okay, the only way we'll get home is
- 好吧，我们回家的唯一办法是
if we reestablish contact with Lonny.
如果我们能重新与Lonny建立联系。
- How are we gonna do that?
- 我们该怎么做呢？
Ricky's gone full baby.
Ricky已经完全像个婴儿了。
- I guess we're just gonna have to do it ourselves.
- 我想我们只能自己动手了。
Here, if I can just reconnect these wires,
来，如果我能把这些线重新接上，
then...
那么...
But they won't reach. - Ahh.
但它们够不到。 - 啊。
We just need something that conducts electricity
我们只需要能导电的东西
that can bridge the connection.
来连接这个断路。
- Too bad we don't have a potato.
- 可惜我们没有土豆。
- Yes, a potato, like we learned in science class.
- 是的，土豆，就像我们在科学课上学的那样。
That's the perfect conductor of electricity.
那是完美的导电体。
- Oh, cool, I was just saying I wish we had a potato.
- 哦，酷，我刚想说希望我们有个土豆。
- Well, we don't have a potato. You know why?
- 好吧，我们没有土豆。你知道为什么吗？
'Cause we're in space!
因为我们是在太空！
- I'm the potato.
- 我就是那个土豆。
all: What?
什么？
- I'm the potato.
我就是那个土豆。
- Come on, you're only at half Ricky.
得了吧，你才发挥了一半的里基实力。
We need you at full Ricky.
我们需要你全力发挥，里基。
- The reason a potato conducts electricity is because
土豆能导电的原因是
it's full of moisture, like my sweaty feet.
它充满了水分，就像我汗湿的脚一样。
- Great, we can use your feet.
太好了，我们可以用你的脚。
- Or, if you don't want to electrocute me,
或者，如果你不想电到我，
we can use my socks.
我们可以用我的袜子。
- I vote feet.
我投脚一票。
- [gags]
（作呕声）
[crackling]
（噼啪声）
- Oh, oh, kids! Kids, are you all right?
哦，哦，孩子们！孩子们，你们还好吗？
- Ricky, you did it!
瑞奇，你做到了！
- Ricky did it?
瑞奇做到了？
My hands are covered in sock juice!
我的手沾满了袜子汁！
- Mom, Dad, we're okay.
妈妈，爸爸，我们没事。
I mean, we're in space, but we're okay.
我是说，我们在太空，但我们没事。
- Well, you're not in space. You're just in a simulator.
嗯，你们不在太空。你们只是在模拟器里。
- I touched Ricky's wet socks for nothing?
我白摸了瑞奇的湿袜子？
- I have a condition!
我有状况！
- Now let me talk you through getting yourselves
现在让我引导你们
out of there.
离开那里。
First, flick that blue toggle switch.
首先，拨动那个蓝色的开关。
It'll turn off the zero gravity simulation control.
它会关闭零重力模拟控制。
- Wait, look at where we are.
等等，看看我们在哪里。
You wanted to go to space, Ricky.
你想到太空去，瑞奇。
And we're kind of already here.
而我们现在差不多就在这里。
So why not enjoy it?
所以为什么不享受一下呢？
- Why not?
为什么不呢？
Even though it's not real, it's still beautiful.
即使这不是真的，它依然很美。
- In the end, you did good, Ricky.
最终，你做得很好，Ricky。
- We all did.
我们大家都做得不错。
Maybe it's okay to not have a life plan just yet.
也许现在还没有人生规划也没关系。
Maybe it's okay to just drift aimlessly for a little while.
也许暂时漫无目的地漂泊一段时间也是可以的。
- Well, I'm really enjoying this view.
嗯，我真的很享受这个景色。
- [laughs]
（笑）
all: Hello, Harpers.
大家好，Harpers。
all: Ahh!
啊！
[thud]
（扑通声）
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
- ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
[whistling]
[口哨声]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶耶耶，耶耶 ♪
♪ 耶耶，耶耶耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ 耶耶耶，耶耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶耶耶耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪